<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home page cover on Chun-Jie Liu | 柳纯洁</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home page cover on Chun-Jie Liu | 柳纯洁</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blink</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-12-26-blink/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-12-26-blink/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m reading the book Blink by Malcolm Gladwell, this is the second book published in 2005 by Gladdwell. His new book Talking to Strangers was released September 2019. I read his book Outliers and David and Goliath published in 2008 and 2013 respectively three years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To be a good organizer</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-12-05-to-be-an-organizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-12-05-to-be-an-organizer/</guid>
      <description>Looking backward the period of one year being a postdoc, I find some flaws, though a lot of flaws root in me, that prohibit me to a good scientific researcher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carrer Plan</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-11-25-carrer-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-11-25-carrer-plan/</guid>
      <description>Are you planing to do research all the time? What do you want from doing research, only for making story to get published?
 The questions above were asked to me by a my very good friend. I think a while and then regard them as serious questions for deliberation. The key point in these two questions are about carrer plan. Before answering these questions directly, I want to share three stories from me and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A letter to my little daughter</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-11-21-a-letter-to-my-daughter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-11-21-a-letter-to-my-daughter/</guid>
      <description>My little daughter was born at June 21th 2019, today she is five month year old. I want to document something about her and my experience as a newbie father. This letter to her I hope she may read in future can understand her father in her growing up.
This can be a series letters at the time points that my paradigm shift for bringing up little girl or misunderstanding occurs between us that I hove no idea how to talk to you directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic writing</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-11-18-academic-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-11-18-academic-writing/</guid>
      <description> Before writing academic papers, you should know - Opinions - Highlights - Evidences
Reading First Key words and concepts Orgnize story Structure </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A father of a daughter</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-10-28-be-a-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-10-28-be-a-father/</guid>
      <description> Role perceptions Role play How to be a father </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rivers of no return</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-10-03-rivers-of-no-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-10-03-rivers-of-no-return/</guid>
      <description>In last one month, I read a novel named &amp;ldquo;Rivers of no return&amp;rdquo; by Ane. After finished reading, I wondered real history in novel of 1978 ~ 2008 about Chinese commercial reform and evolution. Another book &amp;lsquo;China Emerging 1978-2008&amp;rsquo; by Xiaobo Wu came to me. This book described the big commercial and politic news in each year with vivid story and comments.
Rivers of no return This is the novel about three young men</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule process on linux</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-09-17-schedule-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-09-17-schedule-process/</guid>
      <description>Scheduling tasks Automating system maintenance and administration of web server save my life for managing our web server. Scheduling certain tasks to run periodically or one time to backup data and start/stop server at certain time. crontab and at are to service processes to fulfill the requirement of a server manager.
Run periodically crontab The above picture is the crontab rule to schedule periodically tasks. Following code is an example to check MySQL status every five minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configurations</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-09-04-usual-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-09-04-usual-config/</guid>
      <description>The configuration files were deposited into my Gist, but the Gist access was blocked. In case of the not accessing, I copyed some configure files here.
config in .ssh Host * TCPKeepAlive yes ServerAliveInterval 120 ServerAliveCountMax 5 Host guo-4 HostName ip User username Port port Host guo-10 HostName ip User username Port port ProxyJump guo-4 Host guo-3 HostName ip User username Port port ProxyJump guo-4 Host guo-1 HostName ip User username Port port ProxyJump guo-4 Host mgt HostName ip User username Port port  rstudio_bindings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stubborn</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-09-02-stubborn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-09-02-stubborn/</guid>
      <description> Stubborn When talking about word stubborn, what come into my mind is a picture that an old man argue agianst young boy with electronic products addiction. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s my stereotype of old man. So I Google the stubborn, the very image below painted by Louis C Moeller depicts every well with stubborn.
An anecdote Collaboration </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-08-30-github-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-08-30-github-action/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Actions GitHub actions is a automate build, test and deployment product. DockerHub provides automate building by connecting GitHub repo. However, the DockerHub limit the building storage and limit building time.
Automate build and publish to DockerHub Use Jrocker as an exmaple to automate build and publish DockerHub. The code chunk as follows.
on: push name: Build &amp;amp; Push containers jobs: dockerRegistry: name: Docker Registry runs-on: ubuntu-latest steps: - uses: actions/checkout@master - name: Docker Registry uses: actions/docker/login@master env: DOCKER_PASSWORD: ${{ secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogtrottr</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-08-28-blogtrottr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-08-28-blogtrottr/</guid>
      <description>Try to do a little bit writing every night before bed, either writing a journal or a blog (hence I am restarting to blog again), even just for 2-10 min.
 The words above are from X.S. Liu&amp;rsquo;s blog. Shirley is one of greatest scientists in the field of Bioinformatics. I have read almost all the blogs in X.S. Liu&amp;rsquo;s blog when I was in Leng&amp;rsquo;s Lab as a visiting Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>科学上网</title>
      <link>/cn/post/2019-08-28-access-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/post/2019-08-28-access-google/</guid>
      <description>科学上网很多个人博客都有分享，但是每隔一段时间会被删除，就算GitHub shadowsocks也需要做一个rm branch。应该遵守国家相关</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>至暗时刻</title>
      <link>/cn/post/2019-08-16-darkest-hour/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/post/2019-08-16-darkest-hour/</guid>
      <description>Hit Bottom 青年基金落选</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R parallel computation</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-08-15-r-parallel-computation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-08-15-r-parallel-computation/</guid>
      <description>For detailed parallelization, referring to Beyond single core R
 For me, not majored in CS, alwasy hard to comprehend some terms of hardware and software.
Hardware terms  Node: A single motherboard with multiple sockets. Processor/Socket: the silicon containing multiple cores. Core: the unit of computation. Pseudo-cores: can appear to the OS as multiple cores.  Software terms Interpreted languages generally you can only directly work with processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think like a biologist</title>
      <link>/cn/post/2019-08-15-think-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/post/2019-08-15-think-biology/</guid>
      <description>生物信息 生物学家思维逻辑 编程人员思维逻辑 科学发现的故事性 小结</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jrocker - Rstudio and Biocondutor docker</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-08-14-jrocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-08-14-jrocker/</guid>
      <description>Reproducibility Reproducibilities are the main issues in research. For wet biological experiments, though following the protocols of paper provided, sometimes, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to reproduce the same results. Data engineering paper provides code to reproduce the figures and tables, but as the working environment differences, often get unexpected results. Providing Docker image can partly solve the reproducible issues as Guinney states.
Intention I manage several old Ubuntu server before 12.04 with codename precise which many resources don&amp;rsquo;t support the &amp;lsquo;precise&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA-Seq Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/en/project/2019-08-14-machine-learning-for-rna-seq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/project/2019-08-14-machine-learning-for-rna-seq/</guid>
      <description>Seq data interface  RNA-seq  Importing DESeq2 Recount2 Batch effect  miRNA-seq Metabolism Methylation  Machine/Deep Learning interface MLR, Caret, H2O
 Regression model Two class classification Multiclass classification Survival model Cluster analysis Parallel  Shiny package/server  Shiny webserver Shiny bioconductor package  Abortion PIVOT is a great R package for integrative analysis and visualization of transcriptomics data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA-seq data analysis</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-08-24-rnaseq-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-08-24-rnaseq-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Major steps in RNA-seq data analysis.
 Expression design. Quality control. Read alignment. Quantification of gene and transcript levels. Visualization. Differential gene expression. Alternative splicing. Functional analysis. Gene fusion detection. eQTL mapping.  A survey of best practices for RNA-seq data analysis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tumor educated platelet</title>
      <link>/en/post/2019-08-14-tumor-educated-platelet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2019-08-14-tumor-educated-platelet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>博客 - 分享个人见解</title>
      <link>/cn/post/2019-08-14-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/post/2019-08-14-blogging/</guid>
      <description>建站 建立自己的个人博客站分享个人感悟，个人感悟是非常 博客 隐私 框架</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>/en/cv-en/chun-jie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/cv-en/chun-jie/</guid>
      <description>Chun-Jie Liu  Add: HUST, Wuhan, China Email: chunjie.sam.liu@gmail.com Personal website: https://chunjie-sam-liu.life  Education  2014.09 ~ 2018.06, Ph.D, HUST, Wuhan, China 2010.09 ~ 2014.06, B.E., HUST, Wuhan, China   Publications Periodicals   Liu, C. J., Hu, FF., Xia, M., Han, L., Zhang, Q. &amp;amp; Guo, A. Y. (2018). GSCALite: A Web Server for Gene Set Cancer Analysis. Bioinformatics. (PDF)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>简历</title>
      <link>/cn/cv-cn/chun-jie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/cv-cn/chun-jie/</guid>
      <description>柳纯洁 地址：华中科技大学 邮箱：chunjie.sam.liu@gmail.com 个人网站：https://chunjie-sam-liu.l</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install R from source code for ubuntu precise</title>
      <link>/en/post/2018-09-11-install-r-from-source-code-for-ubuntu-precise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2018-09-11-install-r-from-source-code-for-ubuntu-precise/</guid>
      <description>The newest CRAN does not support ubuntu precise anymore.
But some packages need to upgrade the R to &amp;gt; 3.4.0.
So, you have to re-isntall the r from source code, and set repo as &amp;ldquo;cloud.r-project.org&amp;rdquo;, then the install.package will work by install from source code.
options(repos = c(CRAN = &amp;quot;cloud.r-project.org&amp;quot;))  First, you should uninstall the r from the server.
apt-get --purge remove r-base apt-get --purge remove r-base-core apt-get --purge remove r-base-dev apt-get autoremove  Then, download R source code from https://cran.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny deployment</title>
      <link>/en/post/2018-09-11-shiny-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/post/2018-09-11-shiny-deployment/</guid>
      <description>Workspace mode Before pointing workspace to the shiny-server srv directory, change the worksapce mode with g+s.
$chown -R liucj.shiny-apps GSCALite $chmod -R g+s GSCALite $ln -s GSCALite /srv/shiny-server/  Apache2 configuration The add shiny-server configuration to Aapache2. On Ubuntu system, the Apache2 configuration file is 000-default.conf.
The default http 80 port was used for default web directory /var/wwww. Change the proxy with provided port.
RewriteEngine on RewriteCond %{HTTP:Upgrade} !=websocket RewriteRule /web/(.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>